Alan Jenkins

Product Manager

Contact

functionfirst.co.uk Inkdin.me/p/aljenks alan@functionfirst.co.uk 07795 362 980

Hard-working and motivated designer, developer and collaborator with over 15 years of experience. Extensive experience in all aspects of the project life-cycle, working as an individual, team member and manager.

Passionate about product design with a common-sense approach to management. Successfully contributed to and lead several web application projects.

Skills

Axure (Prototyping)

••••

HTML/CSS (Cross-browser experience since IE5.5+. Twitter Bootstrap 2 & 3. Sass/Less CSS)

••••

Adobe Photoshop

••••

Javascript/jQuery

••••

Node.js/NPM/Angular.js

•••00

Microsoft SQL Server (Procedures, Triggers & Views)

00000

ASP.NET (VB, C#, Telerik.NET AJAX Controls, Telerik Reporting)

Version Control (GIT)

••••

Expertise

- Application Development
- Hi & Lo-fidelity Prototyping
- Managing software teams
- User-interface design
- Website design and production
- Wire-framing

Personal

- Attention to detail
- Decision making
- Good Communication & Interpersonal skills
- Team Management
- Mentoring
- Problem solving
- Teamwork

Employment

Product Manager

Claromentis Ltd April 2013 – Present

- Lead a rewrite of the html/css frontend of the entire intranet platform.
- Managed the design and development teams (8)
- Responsible for hiring new developers and designers
- Trained and mentored new designers in html, css and javascript
- Developed prototypes for new intranet apps and features
- Managed various product roadmaps
- Established the product vision, identified enhancements and defined the priority for product development

Web Designer/.Net Developer

Freelance

<u>Gulf Plates</u> (2015 - currently offline)
 SPA web app designed to host live auctions. Built using the MEAN stack with socket.io to push client updates

- <u>Buildmate App</u> (2009 Present)
 VB.NET web application for builders. Designed to help users easily create and manage their building estimates
- <u>Buildmate Website</u> (2009 Present)
 MVC C# website to promote the Buildmate web app.
- Managed the design, development and testing teams (6)
- Provided mentorship and guidance to junior team members
- Contributed to the product vision
- Improved internal design processes
- Scheduled production team
- Build hi-fidelity prototypes for new features and apps
- Project management for PlanetExplore.com and AO.com intranets

UI Designer

Claromentis Ltd

Senior UI Designer

August 2010 - April 2013

Claromentis Ltd

May 2009 – August 2010

- Designed mock-up's for new clients
- Built interfaces based on mock-up's
- Project management for PlanetExplore.com and AO.com intranets
- Liaised with third-party providers and managed project schedules

Web Designer/ASP Developer

Northbloc Ltd

March 2006 - September 2007

 Designed and developed several projects including ecommerce and holiday booking systems

Web Designer/ASP Developer

The Creative Cake Ltd

February 2003 – March 2006

- Designed and developed of several ecommerce and CMS systems including Annsummers.com
- Requirements gathering
- Wrote tender specifications

Web Designer/ASP Developer

Worldsearch Internet Ltd July 2000 – February 2003 Designed and developed ecommerce and CMS systems, including Ritz Fine Jewellery

Education

1995 - 1997

1990 - 1995

- Hartlepool College of Further Education BTEC ND in Engineering
- English Martyrs School & Sixth Form College GCSE - 8 Grade C+

Interests

- Drawing & Sketching
- Reading
- Cycling
- Illustration